# Davide Marchini

Born in Fidenza (Italy) on October  $7^{th}$ , 1994.

Italian citizen.

Permanent resident in the United Kingdom (UK).

☑ davide.marchini1@gmail.com

marchinidavide.github.io

**\** +447999081135

in marchinidavide

narchinidavide

## Summary

Quantitative researcher professional with focus on Machine Learning, systematic investing and  $\alpha$ -design. Experienced in macroeconomic dynamics of emerging and frontier markets. Research interests at the intersection of memory augmented neural architectures, self-learning algorithms and time series modelling.

# Experience

#### Winton Capital London, United Kingdom

Quantitative Researcher

09/2019 - present 02/2019 - 05/2019

*Intern* (*Zurich*, *Switzerland*)

Research and development of systematic investment strategies.

## **Independent Research**

Development of algorithmic investment strategies

06/2018 - present

Research on Memory Augmented Neural Architectures, Self-Learning Algorithms, Adversarial Inputs, Generative Models, (Differentiable) Performance Metrics. Implementation of an advanced backtesting engine (order book reconstruction, simulations of multi-agent and multi-asset markets) and design of proprietary libraries for performance and risk analytics, transaction cost analysis and visualization.

#### Vontobel Asset Management

Zurich, Switzerland

Portfolio and Risk Analyst

12/2017 - 01/2019

Part-time position (working student 40-60%) in the Portfolio and Risk Analytics Team. Responsibilities over risk analysis, process automation and data reconciliation. Development and maintenance of tools in R (Sweave, caret, ggplot2), SQL, Excel VBA, Bloomberg and Morningstar.

## University of Zurich - Department of Banking and Finance

Zurich, Switzerland

(Co-) Portfolio Manager, AuM €2Mn

02/2017 - 05/2018

Member of the Macro Group in the Portfolio Management Program (PMP), an academic collaboration between University of Zurich, ZZ Vermögensberatung (Schweiz) AG and P&K Pühringer Gemeinnützigen Stiftung. Management of an Emerging and Frontier Markets portfolio focused on Fixed Income and FX with responsibilities over market research, model development, trading and periodic presentations.

## **Education**

#### ETH Zurich and University of Zurich

Zurich, Switzerland

Master of Science in Quantitative Finance, CGPA: 5.6/6.0

2016 - 2019

M.Sc. Thesis: "Consistent Scenario Generation of Financial Time Series" - Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Erich Walter Farkas.

Relevant modules: Computational finance, Quantitative portfolio management, Machine and Deep Learning, Financial Engineering. Semester projects: ML techniques in FX Instruments, Optimal shrinkage of the covariance matrix, Ranked portfolio optimization. **Associations**: Zurich Quantitative Finance Alumni (ZQFA). **Grants**: *LGT Capital Partners* Scholarship (Fr.1500).

Politecnico di Milano Milan, Italy

Bachelor of Science in Mathematical Engineering

2013 - 2016

**B.Sc.** Thesis: "A mathematical model for crime diffusion" - Supervisor: Prof. Maurizio Verri.

Relevant modules: Mathematical Analysis and PDEs, Numerical Analysis, Computer Science, Probability Theory, Statistical Inference. Exchange semester: Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (UAM) (Real and Functional Analysis, Operations Research). 09/2015 - 01/2016 **Associations**: Assiociazione Ingegneri Matematici (AIM) **Grants**: INVALSI 2013 (€500), Erasmus+ 2015 (€2500)

### Interests and Skills

Languages: Italian (native), English and Spanish (fluent), French (conversational).

Research interests: Memory Augmented Neural Architectures, Self-Learning Algorithms, Time Series Modelling.

Programming proficiency: Python (pandas, pytorch, sklearn), R, Matlab, C/C++, SQL, MS Office (incl. Excel VBA), LATEX. Certificates: Bloomberg Markets Concepts (BMC) for Bloomberg Terminal.

High School: Math Olympiad; Summer Schools at Ducati Motors, SNS Pisa, University of Parma, Bocconi University.

Soft skills: Capable team player, trained to work under pressure and deadlines, precise, detail observer, fast learner.